Guide to the Dorothy Norman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- April 1997 Acquisition, 1908-1996; 4; 54.38; 55 boxes
  - Correspondence and Subject Files
    - Leary, Timothy, 1960-1961, undated (Box 138)
    - Leeto, Alida, 1952-1960, undated (Box 138)
    - Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1950-1956 (Box 138)
    - Lotte, Lenya, 1959 (Box 138)
    - Lerman, Leo, 1953, undated; 2 (Box 138)
    - Lescaze, William, 1961, 1969 (Box 138)
    - Levi, Carlo, 1947-1960 (Box 138)
    - Levy, Adele, 1950-1960, undated (Box 138)
    - Levy, G. Rachel (Gertrude Rachel), 1958-1961 (Box 138)
    - Lewisohn, Margaret, 1950-1959 (Box 138)
    - Leyden, Rudolf von, 1964-1966, undated; 2 (Box 138)
    - Library of Congress, 1952-1969 (Box 139)
    - Liggett, Coventry, 1961 (Box 139)
    - Lowe, Sue, 1952-1958, undated (Box 139)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1937-1948 (Box 139)
    - Lutyens, Phyllis Warburg, 1950-1954, undated (Box 139)
    - Lyons, Edward, 1947, 1960 (Box 139)
    - "M" General, 1939-1970, undated; 4 (Box 139)
    - Magnes, Beatrice, 1950 (Box 139)
    - Malraux, André, 1945 (Box 139)
    - Manchester, John, 1974 (Box 139)
    - Maney, Richard, 1957, undated (Box 139)
    - Mann, Thomas, 1937-1945 (Box 139)
    - Jacobi, Lotte, 1961 (Box 139)
    - Marboro Book Club, 1957-1960 (Box 139)
    - Margules, De Hirsh, 1961-1964 (Box 139)
    - Marin, John, 1954-1984, undated; 2 (Box 139)
    - Marin, John C., Jr., 1951; 2 (Box 139)
    - May, Rollo, 1970 (Box 139)
    - May, Wilfred, 1941-1959, undated (Box 139)
    - McCarthy, Mary, 1953 (Box 139)
    - McCausland, Elizabeth, 1940 (Box 139)
    - McCray, Porter A., 1961 (Box 139)
    - Mead, Cynthia, 1960, undated (Box 139)
    - Mellquist, Jerome, 1937-1953; 3 (Box 139)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.), 1947-1972 (Box 139)
    - Meyer, Agnes Ernst, 1946-1953; 2 (Box 139)
    - Meyer, Grace, 1969-1970 (Box 139)
    - Miller, Frances, 1955-1956, undated (Box 139)
    - Miller, Jeffrey, 1974 (Box 139)
    - Miracle, Anne, undated (Box 139)
    - Mitchel, Sally, 1952-1955, undated (Box 139)
    - Mondrian, Piet, 1937-1941; 2 (Box 139)
    - Moore, Henry, 1938 (Box 139)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1937-1947; 2 (Box 139)
    - Morgenthau, Henry Jr. & Morgenthau, Henry, III., 1950-1951, undated (Box 139)
    - Morris, Wright, 1942 (Box 139)
    - Morton, Jim & Taylor, Frances Henry, 1950-1954, undated (Box 139)
    - Mountbatten of Burma, Edwina Ashley Mountbatten, Countess, 1951-1959 (Box 139)
    - Muse, Mary, 1947 (Box 139)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1964-1965 (Box 139)
    - Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.), 1948-1972 (Box 139)
    - "N" General, 1950-1963, undated; 2 (Box 139)
    - Naoroji, Kish A. D., 1952-1962 (Box 139)
    - Nath, Shiam, 1960-1965 (Box 139)
    - National Gallery of Art (U.S.), 1954 (Box 139)
    - Naumberg, George & Cecile, 1951-1956, undated (Box 139)
    - Nehru, B. K., 1950-1975, undated (Box 139)
    - Nehru, J. (empty folder), undated (Box 139)
    - Neumann, Erich, 1958-1959, undated (Box 139)
    - Newberry Library, 1968, undated (Box 139)
    - Newhall, Beaumont & Nancy, 1946-1975, undated; 2 (Box 139)
    - Niebuhr, Dr., 1937 (Box 140)
    - Nijinsky, Romola de Pulszky, 1937, 1940 (Box 140)
    - Nin, Anaïs, 1937-1964 (Box 140)
    - Nivola, Costantino, 1984 (Box 140)
    - Nivola, Ruth, undated (Box 140)
    - Norfolk Museum, 1959 (Box 140)
    - Norton, D. H., 1939 (Box 140)
    - "O" General, 1940-1963 (Box 140)
    - O'Campo, Victoria, 1960-1968, undated; 2 (Box 140)
    - O'Dwyer, Sloan, 1951, undated (Box 140)
    - Okamura, Mihoko, 1956-1974; 2 (Box 140)
    - O'Keefe, John, 1976, 1982 (Box 140)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1954-1974 (Box 140)
    - Olson, Charles, circa 1937-1939; 2 (Box 140)
    - O'Neill, Eugene, 1937, undated; 2 (Box 140)
    - Osborn, Fairfield, 1961-1962, undated (Box 140)
    - O'Sullivan, Paul, 1952-1954, undated (Box 140)
    - Oxford Book & Stationery Co., 1950-1953 (Box 140)
    - "P" General, 1938-1963, undated; 2 (Box 140)
    - Pandit, Nan, 1940-1950 (Box 140)
    - Pandit, R. (empty folder), undated (Box 140)
    - Pandit, V. L. & Nayantara, Sahgal, 1948-1970; 2 (Box 140)
    - Pandy, Jim, 1959 (Box 140)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, 1954 (Box 140)
    - Patchen, Kenneth, undated (Box 140)
    - Paz, Octavio & Maria Jo, 1973-1976 (Box 140)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1969-1972 (Box 140)
    - Plaut, Richard, 1950-1956, undated (Box 140)
    - Porter, Eliot, 1946-1951, undated (Box 140)
    - Potter, Jeffrey, 1954-1955, undated (Box 140)
    - Poupard-Lieussou, Y. (Yves), 1958-1963 (Box 140)
    - "Q" General, undated (Box 140)
    - "R " General, 1938-1963, undated; 2 (Box 140)
    - Radhakrishnan, S., Dr., 1952-1964, undated; 3 (Box 140)
    - Rainer, Luise (Knittel), 1940-1983, undated; 2 (Box 140)
    - Rajagopalachari, C. (Chakravarti), 1950-1954 (Box 140)
    - Rao, Kitty Verstaendig, 1950-1957 (Box 140)
    - Rao, Raja, 1956-1993, undated (Box 140)
    - Rao, Shanta, 1963-1972 (Box 140)
    - Ravagli, Angelo, undated (Box 140)
    - Reis, Claire, 1951-1959, undated (Box 140)
    - Riboud, Jean, 1950, 1958 (Box 140)
    - Richardson, Dorothy, circa 1938-1940; 2 (Box 140)
    - Richman, Robert, 1952, 1958 (Box 140)
    - Richter, Hans, 1946; 2 (Box 140)
    - Riding, Laura, 1937 (Box 140)
    - Ringel, Fred, 1932-1937 (Box 140)
    - Robina, Hanna, 1950 (Box 140)
    - Rodakiewicz, Henwar, 1971-1974, undated; 2 (Box 140)
    - Rolo, Charles, 1950 (Box 140)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1932-1946; 4 (Box 140)
    - Rosenwald, Judy, 1956 (Box 140)
    - Ross, Cary, 1938-1948, undated; 2 (Box 140)
    - Rosset, Barney, 1954-1960 (Box 140)
    - Rote, John, 1951-1953, undated (Box 140)
    - Rovina, Hannah, 1950, undated (Box 140)
    - Roy, Jamini, 1953-1982; 2 (Box 140)
    - Roy, Sunil K., 1960-1974, undated (Box 140)
    - "S" General, 1938-1967, undated; 3 (Box 141)
    - Sabavala, Roshan, 1952-1957 (Box 141)
    - Saint-John Perse, 1934-1973, undated (Box 141)
    - Salvemini, Gaetano, 1943-1944 (Box 141)
    - Santayana, George, 1937 (Box 141)
    - Sarabhai, Bharati, 1952-1959 (Box 141)
    - Saroyan, William, undated (Box 141)
    - Saunders, Gene, 1961-1962, undated (Box 141)
    - Schack, William, 1956-1958 (Box 141)
    - Schaefer, Bertha, undated (Box 141)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr., 1961 (Box 141)
    - Schnitzler, H., 1940 (Box 141)
    - Schubart, Dorothy, 1956-1958, undated (Box 141)
    - Schubart, Selma Stieglitz, 1946 (Box 141)
    - Schwartz, Delmore, 1937-1938 (Box 141)
    - Seaver, Ed, 1961-1965, undated; 2 (Box 141)
    - Seligmann, Herbert J. (Herbert Jacob), 1946-1947, undated; 2 (Box 141)
    - Sethi, Rajeev, 1984 (Box 141)
    - Shapiro, Meyer, 1946, 1964 (Box 141)
    - Sheean, Vincent, 1959-1964 (Box 141)
    - Sherman, Paul, 1960 (Box 141)
    - Silone, Ignazio & Darina, 1937-1987, undated; 4 (Box 141)
    - Simpson, Helen, 1950-1957, undated (Box 141)
    - Sindhi, Vimla, 1950-1963 (Box 141)
    - Singh, Madanjeet, 1950-1957, undated (Box 141)
    - Singh, Natwar, 1964-1975 (Box 141)
    - Sitwell, Edith, 1949, undated; 2 (Box 141)
    - Slochower, Harry, 1942 (Box 141)
    - Smedsrud, Halvor Lagercrantz, 1953, undated (Box 141)
    - Spaeth, Otto Lucien, 1957-1962, undated (Box 141)
    - Spender, Stephen, 1948-1955 (Box 141)
    - Steichen, Clara, 1947-1949 (Box 141)
    - Steichen, Edward, 1950-1963, undated (Box 141)
    - Stein, Leo, 1947, undated (Box 141)
    - Steinberg, Saul & Sterne, Hedda, 1950-1955, undated (Box 141)
    - Stinnes, Edmund Hugo, 1960 January 3 (Box 141)
    - Strand, Paul, 1930-1976, undated; 2 (Box 141)
    - Strasser, Peter, 1959 November 17 (Box 141)
    - Stratou, Dora, 1952-1962 (Box 141)
    - Straus, Ann Elizabeth, 1940-1941, undated (Box 141)
    - Straus, Hugh Grant & Flora, 1950-1958, undated (Box 141)
    - Suzuki, Daisetz Teitaro, 1955-1962; 2 (Box 141)
    - Sweeney, J. F., undated; 2 (Box 141)
    - Swope, Gerard, Jr., 1957-1960 (Box 141)
    - Sykes, Gerald, 1957-1976, undated (Box 141)
    - "T" General, 1959-1964 (Box 142)
    - Talmey, Allene, 1950-1960 (Box 142)
    - Thompson, Dorothy, undated (Box 142)
    - Tibón, Gutierre, 1973-1976; 2 (Box 142)
    - Tillich, Hannah, 1964-1969, undated; 4 (Box 142)
    - Trocmé, Jean & Pat, 1954-1965, undated (Box 142)
    - "U" General, 1952, 1956 (Box 142)
    - "V" General, 1952-1962 (Box 142)
    - Valentin, A., undated (Box 142)
    - Varèse, Edgard, 1937-1963, undated; 2 (Box 142)
    - "W " General, 1935-1964, undated; 2 (Box 142)
    - Wadia, Pilly, 1950, 1955 (Box 142)
    - Wasserman, William & Marion, 1953, undated (Box 142)
    - Wasserstrom, William, 1960-1963 (Box 142)
    - Watts, Alan, 1957-1974 (Box 142)
    - Weber, Brom, 1970-1973 (Box 142)
    - Wertham, Frederic, 1960 January 7 (Box 142)
    - Westman, Heinz, 1956-1965, undated (Box 142)
    - Wheeler, Monroe, 1954-1960, undated; 3 (Box 142)
    - Wheeler, Wilfred & Emily, 1938-1968, undated (Box 142)
    - White, Minor, 1955-1970; 3 (Box 142)
    - Whitehill, Jean L., 1950-1953, undated (Box 142)
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1934-1966; 3 (Box 142)
    - Wolff, Helen & Kurt, 1952-1971 (Box 142)
    - Wright, Cora, 1959 (Box 142)
    - Zayas, Marius de, 1954 (Box 142)
    - Zevi, Tullia, 1953 (Box 142)
    - Zoler, E. C., 1950-1959 (Box 142)
    - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1911-1984; 15 (Box 143)
    - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1925-1988; 24 (Box 144)
    - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1936-1994; 25 (Box 145)
    - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1921-1937; 27 (Box 146)
    - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1938-1986; 24 (Box 147)
    - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1933-1936; 10 (Box 148)
  - Personal and Professional Papers
    - School notes
      - Miscellaneous school notes, undated; 4 (Box 149)
      - "Dorothy Stecker / Music 12a", 1922 (Box 149)
      - "Sociology I: Race Differences, Prepared by Carl Kelsey", undated (Box 149)
      - Notes, miscellaneous, 1921-1924, undated; 2 (Box 149)
    - "Stieglitz Expenses", 1971-1973 (Box 149)
    - "O'Keeffe", 1977-1989 (Box 149)
      Includes newspaper clippings and articles.
    - "O'Keeffe Books 1989 / Roxana Robinson / Mrs. Sisler / Letters to N. Talese, Roxana Robinson / Notes on Sue Lowe Book." General correspondence, letters & transcript copies, various articles, reviews, 1951-1994 (Box 149)
    - "Stieglitz -- 1978 to --." Miscellaneous correspondence, articles, postcards, exhibition announcements, catalogues, reviews. Including Alfred Stieglitz, Catalogue c. 1977 & Stieglitz and the Photo-Secession: Pictorialism to Modernism 1902-17", 1951-1988, undated (Box 150)
    - "Paul Strand." Articles, writings; drawing, 1983, undated (Box 150)
    - Envelope from Princeton University Press. Enclosed: article entitled, "Rudy: An Intimate Portrait of Rudolph Valentino by his Wife Natacha Rambova", 1977 (Box 150)
    - The New Criterion. Volume I, Number 10, 1983 June (Box 150)
    - [From box labelled: "To office on 3rd floor--Diaries & Notebooks: 1918-46, n.d."]
      - Journal, "Dorothy S. Norman: Nov. 1930 - March 1931/ Book 4 / D.S.N." 152 pp., 1930-1931 (Box 151)
      - "Journal, Book No. VII: Dorothy Norman: Aug. 31. 33", 1933 (Box 151)
      - "Dorothy S. Norman: Book 5: March 1931 - July 4, 1932" 153 pp., 1931-1932 (Box 151)
      - Bound notebook, entitled "Index (alphabetical) of Stieglitz Stories", undated (Box 151)
      - Various notebooks, miscellaneous writing exercises, 1926-1929, undated (Box 151)
      - Notebook. One side reads, "DN Notes: 1946 etc.," the other side labelled, "Angna Enters: Notebook DN", 1964 (Box 151)
      - The Wanamaker Diary, 1918 (Box 151)
      - "The Scribble-In Book," diary, undated (Box 151)
      - "Not Identified / To be signed." Miscellaneous poems and writings, 1949, undated (Box 151)
      - Various notebooks, undated (Box 151)
      - Journal. "Dorothy S. Norman", 1930 (Box 151)
      - "The Scribble-In Book," diary. 110 pp., Miscellaneous notebook, undated (Box 151)
      - The Wanamaker Diary, 1919-1920 (Box 151)
      - Miscellaneous notebook, "finished '47", 1941-1947? (Box 151)
    - [From box labelled: "Twice A Year/ TAY inserts"]
      - Folder of blank paper, undated (Box 152)
      - "Inserts for TAY/ Issue I." Twice A Year: A Semi-Annual Journal ", 1938 (Box 152)
      - Blank postcards, Twice A Year Press; a few cards with addresses, undated; 5 (Box 152)
      - Inserts for TAY/ issue 2, Copy of The New York Herald Tribune: stamped at the top, "Twice A Year: Insert: Issue No. II" Jan. 27, 1939 (Box 152)
      - TAY blank labels & a few additional TAY blank postcards, undated; 3 (Box 152)
      - The New York Herald Tribune: stamped, "Twice A Year: Insert: Issue No. II Jan. 27, 1939 (107 copies), 8 (Box 152)
    - [From box labelled: "D. N. Papers, 'Twice A Year'--original proposals for, correspondence regarding; orders for; etc.; From gray office file cabinet. Moved 2/93 by D. R."]
      - "TAY orders - Paid & Finished/ Paid & Completed", 1959-1964 (Box 153)
      - "TAY orders to be filled", 1953-1960 (Box 153)
      - "TAY - Correspondence & Orders." Announcement re Stieglitz Memorial Portfolio: 1864 - 1946, ed. & pubd. by Dorothy Norman, 1958-1959, undated (Box 153)
      - "TAY Anthology - Introduction.", undated (Box 153)
      - "TAY - Proposed Anthology - American Writing = for India," miscellaneous notes, news article, 1951-1952 (Box 153)
      - "TAY - Proposed Anthology - Indian Writings for America", 1952, undated (Box 153)
      - "TAY Anthology - Proposed Table of Contents." Art & Auction Catalogue by D. N., proposal letters, undated (Box 153)
      - "Form Letters re Stieglitz material." Folder labelled, "Letters asking for Stieglitz Letters & Material / (1st letter)", undated (Box 153)
      - "Letter to people who never answered request for Stieglitz letters", 1949 (Box 153)
      - "Letter to people who sent Stieglitz letters", 1949 (Box 153)
      - "Letter to Stieglitz & Marin publications", 1949 (Box 153)
      - "Lists regarding Stieglitz Letters"/ "Stieglitz letter lists", undated (Box 153)
      - "Typed Lists for DSN", undated (Box 153)
      - "Stieglitz letter list - Triplicate for our files", undated (Box 153)
      - "Missing Prints in Camera Work sets", undated (Box 153)
      - "Lists of Stieglitz letters", undated (Box 153)
      - "Thompson Signal Device (E.H.)"/ "Thompson Signal" Bills, records, receipts, 1969-1976 (Box 153)
      - "Stieglitz Letter lists", undated (Box 153)
      - "Notes, etc. relating to research material - Results incorporated in bibliography", 1947-1948, undated (Box 153)
      - "Lists of Stieglitz letter file", undated (Box 153)
    - [From box labelled: "(Box 2 of 2)/ D. N. Papers/ 'TAY - original proposals for; corresp. regarding; orders for; etc.' From grey office file cabinet, moved 2/93 by DR"]
      - "Stieglitz Book -- Letters about -", 1925-1957 (Box 154)
      - "1 set small (?) pictures from TAY issues.", undated (Box 154)
      - "Juley, Peter." Correspondence, 1946 (Box 154)
      - "TAY - Correspondence. About 1964-65-70", 1964-1974, undated (Box 154)
      - "Libraries (Letters in regards to Twice A Year sets) - 1975"/ "Letters to Libraries in regards DN proposed gift of TAY" (Box 154)
      - "TAY - Orders -", 1961-1975 (Box 154)
    - Encounters: master galleys, undated; 3 (Box 155)
    - [From box labelled: "D. N. Papers / "Marin'"]
      - "Appraisals 1976-80"/ "H-O." Doesn't correspond with this material. "Contract for: The Selected Writings of John Marin & documents relating to royalties/ contract removed & mailed certified to D.N., E.H., 8/12/69", 1949-1951 (Box 156)
      - "New York Times Review of Selected Writings of John Marin" [9 copies] & issue of Doubleday National Bestsellers, 1949 December (Box 156)
      - "Marin - Notes & material used in earlier (long) version of Introduction"/ "Marin file", undated (Box 156)
      - "Relating to Marin." Personal correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 156)
      - "John Marin: a few notes." Photocopied selections, undated (Box 156)
      - "Marin, John"/ "DN/ John Marin / (& John Jr.) Correspondence.", 1923-1949, undated (Box 156)
      - Various publishing correspondence, 1947-1964 (Box 156)
      - "Marin Folder/ Ms. Marin - Notes & Conversations - Carbons." Miscellaneous ms. materials, previously unpublished, 1955, undated (Box 156)
    - "Twice A Year -- basement Inventory (not up to date)," miscellaneous records, 1964-1976, undated (Box 157)
    - "U."/ "NORMAN/ All Copies Used." Copy of The New Republic, January 30, 1989 issue with a note attached: "5 copies of each checked / page", 1989 January (Box 157)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1961-1994, undated; 4 (Box 157)
    - [From box labelled: "Box 2 of 2, Office 3rd flr 1994]
      - Letters from Edward A. Norman to his parents, 1908-1929; 8 (Box 158)
      - Letters from Andrew E. Norman to his parents, news clippings, correspondence, miscellaneous, 1935-1950, undated; 2 (Box 158)
    - [From box labelled: "Letters"]
      - Miscellaneous undated writings, 3 (Box 158)
      - The Sitwells in the Same Room, circa 1918-1950; 5 (Box 158)
        Includes various drafts, notes, and correspondence.
      - The Sitwells in the Same Room, circa 1918-1950; 8 (Box 159)
      - Bronze keepsake, undated (Box 159)
    - "Drafts of D.N./ Writings, poems, etc.", 1940-1946, undated; 2 (Box 159)
    - [From box labelled: "Indira, India notes, 'Encounters' ms., 12/90"]
      - "American Aid for Freedom: lists & correspondence"; "American Aid for Freedom: Lists (Old)," correspondence, brochures, news articles; American Correspondence, 1948-1951, undated (Box 159)
      - "American Aid for Freedom: Correspondence"; "American Aid for Freedom: Corresp., checks"; "American Aid for Freedom: Expenses & Contributions", 1950-1952 (Box 159)
      - Folder with miscellaneous papers, warranties, miscellaneous note, undated (Box 159)
      - "Gandhi's Assassination" writings, 1948 (Box 159)
      - Misc. writings, correspondence with the Prime Minister of New Delhi, 1950-1960 (Box 159)
      - Misc. writings, correspondence, "1965- 69 & 70s / Extra copies / Unsorted", 1960-1973 (Box 159)
      - Misc. writings, correspondence, "1960- 64 / Extra copies & unsorted", 1957-1966 (Box 159)
      - Misc. writings, correspondence, "1970's / Extra copies / (unsorted)", 1970-1976 (Box 159)
      - Misc. writings, correspondence, "Extra copies / 1980s" & 1 pamphlet in memory of Indira Gandhi, 1980-1984 (Box 160)
      - "I.G./ Early Ms." Ms. copy, 1984-1985 (Box 160)
      - Misc. notes, correspondence re: I.G., 1960-1987 (Box 160)
      - "Lists - Comp Copies/ I.G. Letters" re: Indira Gandhi: Correspondence with Dorothy Norman", 1985 April (Box 160)
      - Full set of corrected pages (re: Encounters), List of "Photographs: Indira Gandhi Book of Letters" & "Illustrations to Come", 1966; 2 (Box 160)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, various writings re Indira Gandhi, entitled Letters to Indira Gandhi of Dorothy Norman, miscellaneous mailings and publications, 1951-1985, undated; 2 (Box 160)
    - [From box labelled, "Dorothy Norman Papers 1989; Books (tantra), etc."]
      - Miscellaneous correspondence. Mislabeled "A - I." Misc. folders, "To be arranged alphabetically." 1 labelled "Chrono. order: DN in India Jan - Mar 1950," 1 labelled "Others," 2 empty folders, 1944-1950, undated (Box 160)
      - "Miscellaneous Indians, Etc." Corresp., & "To Do When Nothing Else to do!": misc. news articles, exhibition announcements; "Important: To hold: At Each Moment Anew: DN Poems / Square Dance??: MEMOIR 1/77 To Do Over"; "Venturi conversation etc. & quotes / memoir", 1945-1977, undated (Box 160)
      - "DN MS. in re: Indira Gandhi"/ "Felicitation Vol. to Mrs. Gandhi 7/3/72"; "Anup Singh / J.J. Singh / D.N. to & from"; "DN: Correspondence, notes / Nelvin book" Misc. professional corresp.; "'Pandit Gels' to DN From DN", 1943-1972, undated (Box 160)
      - Miscellaneous "Correspondence / DN to & from Aijar, Asaf Ali, Bhabha, Sarabhai, Sundarani"; "Sri Aurobindo Miscellaneous", 1947-1975, undated (Box 160)
      - "Faust" Miscellaneous writings, typewritten ms. pages, undated (Box 160)
      - Miscellaneous writings & 1 issue of " Show: The Magazine of the Performing Arts " w/ India articles, 1960-1962, undated (Box 160)
      - "Material on Aid, DN's Committee for India, etc.", 1952-1963, undated (Box 160)
      - "The Hero and Numbers, etc." Various writings, manuscripts; "Reynal- Morrow Pantheon Myth"; 2 copies of Royal Albums, full-size pages; "Leo Oppenheim; Gilgamesh", undated (Box 161)
      - Misc. manuscript materials of various sacred texts (similar to materials in previous folder) including the Bhagavad Gita; museum announcements & bulletins, 1955-1958, undated (Box 161)
    - [From box labelled: "'Morgan Library' file, misc. art catalogues"]
      - "Morgan Library" Letters, announcements & New York Times Exhibition review, 1968-1973 (Box 161)
      - "Loan Exhibition of Flemish Primitives: October 26 to November 16 1929: F. Kleinberger Galleries, Inc., N.Y." Various art exhibition invitations & catalogues, magazines, arts programs, 1929-1935, undated (Box 161)
      - Art catalogues, exhibition lists, 1924-1935, undated; 2 (Box 161)
      - Misc. art catalogues: Archaologie; Canadian Fine Crafts 1966/67; The Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin 1968; Dragons: Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1966-1968, undated (Box 161)
      - Miscellaneous art catalogues, including Bibliofilo Romano; Navajo Creation Myth: Bulletin of the Museum of Navajo Ceremonial Art; Early Travels: History of Discovery; The Bulletin of The Cleveland Museum of Art; & The Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin Dec. 1962. Miscellaneous art invitations, 1941-1962, undated (Box 161)
      - Miscellaneous art catalogues & exhibition announcements, including Hesperia Art Bulletin; Indonesian Art: The Brooklyn Museum; The American - Jewish Tercentenary 1654-54, The University Museum, University of Pennsylvania; Jackson Pollock 1951, Betty Parsons' Gallery, NY [2 copies]; Lucien Goldschmidt [Galleries], NY; ARTNEWS, Jan. 1957, 1951-1959, undated (Box 161)
      - Personal correspondence "1934-35", 1926-1937, undated; 3 (Box 161)
      - "Personal correspondence CA 1936" letters, postcards, 1935-1937, undated; 2 (Box 161)
      - "Personal correspondence CA 1937" letters, postcards, 1937, undated; 2 (Box 161)
      - "Personal letters vol. 2" Postcards, folder labelled "Miracle Chazanoff/ B Lamb," personal corresp., 1928-1947, undated; 3 (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933", 1925-1926 (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933" Filed under "A - 1925" (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933" Filed under "B - 1926", 1926, undated (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933" Filed under "C - 1927", 1927-1929, undated (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933" Filed under "C - 1928" (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933" Filed under "E - 1929" (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933" Filed under "G - 1930", 1930-1931, undated (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933" Filed under "HIJ - 1931" 1 letter (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933" Filed under "KL - 1932", 1932-1937, undated (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933" Filed under "M - 1933", 1932-1933, undated; 2 (Box 162)
      - "Personal letters 1925-26 & 1933" Filed under "NO - undated letters, announcements, invitations", 2 (Box 162)
    - [From box labelled, "Indira, India notes, 'Encounters' ms. 12/90"-- Folder "Gandhi's Assassination" was taken from this file]
      - "Indira Gandhi by DN" Ms. letters, writings, news articles; "Dahlberg" / "Cech Dahlberg" Ms. copy 1984 Nov 30 issue of India Today & 1984 Nov 12 issue of Time w/ articles on Indira Gandhi's death, 1950-1984 (Box 162)